<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<text>
		<content>Muz</content>
		<content>Muz, what's your story?</content>
		<content>Sitting in the dark tends to make the mind wander.</content>
		<content>During the hurricane,</content>
		<content>I thought of a time before electricity</content>
		<content>when people used stories</content>
		<content>to explain the world around them</content>
		<content>and to pass the hours by.</content>
		<content>Back then,</content> <!-- text 8 -->
		<content>storms were not weather</content>
		<content>but the wrath of angry gods in the sky.</content>
		<content>I, of course, knew better.</content>
		<content>Still,</content> <!-- line 12 -->
		<content>I began to think about New York,</content>
		<content>about all of us here,</content>
		<content>and about what might be happening</content>
		<content>out there in the storm,</content>
		<content id="style"><style>about </style><style id="italic">who</style><style> might be out there in the storm.</style></content>
		<content>Sitting in the dark tends to make the mind wander.</content> <!-- line 18 -->
		<content>Muz Entertainment</content> <!-- line 19 -->
		<content>presents</content>
		<content>When the Lights</content> <!-- line 21 -->
		<content>Went Out</content>
		<content>stories, artwork, music, photography and programming by</content> <!-- line 23 -->
		<content>Kelly Dougher</content>
		<content>Ricardo Morales</content>
		<content>Stefan Orzech</content>
		<content>Nara Strete</content>
		<content>200 people dead</content> <!-- line 28 -->
		<content>380,000 houses damaged or destroyed</content>
		<content id="style"><style id="break">200 million gallons</style><style>of untreated sewage</style></content>
		<content>7.5 million without power</content>
		<content>$65.5 billion in damages</content>
		<content>19,000 flights cancelled</content><!-- line 33 -->
		<content>scribbling in notebooks</content> <!-- line 34 -->
		<content>sketching images</content>
		<content>strumming guitar chords</content>
		<content id="style"><style>At the end of October, a hurricane </style><style id="dark">left us in the dark...</style></content> <!-- line 37 --> <!-- End of Introduction -->
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content>Before the Hurricane</content> <!-- line 50 --> <!-- Beginning of Before the Hurricane -->
		<content>Wind outside the motel window shrills,</content>
		<content>then dissipates.</content>
		<content>I've been awake for hours</content>
		<content>It’s too warm in here</content>
		<content>The hurricane should have arrived by now.</content> <!-- line 55 -->
		<content>I rise from the bed,</content>
		<content>cross the room,</content>
		<content>lift the curtain.</content>
		<content>But there's nothing out there.</content> <!-- line 59 -->
		<content>just an empty parking lot</content>
		<content>a bit of rain</content>
		<content>a stray cat making its way across the street</content>
		<content>I put on a jacket and walk outside.</content> <!-- line 63 -->
		<content>The cold air clears my mind.</content>
		<content>I lean against the door.</content>
		<content>A blast of wind rattles the motel window.</content>
		<content>The smell of central Pennsylvania,</content> <!-- line 67 -->
		<content>the stark, fresh valley smell,</content>
		<content id="style"><style>reminds me of </style><style id="dark">drunken college years.</style></content>
		<content>I miss this place.</content>
		<content>Tomorrow, I'll drive through the hurricane.</content> <!-- line 71 -->
		<content id="style"><style id="italic">I have a business to run</style></content>
		<content id="style"><style id="italic">contracts to prepare</style></content>
		<content id="style"><style id="italic">meetings to attend</style></content>
		<content>The wind picks up,</content>
		<content>then dies down,</content>
		<content id="style"><style>and my </style><style id="portal">soul is in Manhattan.</style></content> <!-- line 77 -->
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content>You</content> <!-- line 90 --> <!-- Beginning of Storm Song Interlude -->
		<content>and</content>
		<content>I</content>	
		<content>waves</content> <!-- line 93 -->
		<content>sky</content>
		<content>going under</content> <!-- line 95 -->
		<content>I cannot swim</content>
		<content>lightning</content> <!-- line 97 -->
		<content>thunder</content>
		<content>cast me out</content> <!-- line 99 -->
		<content>we could never be more</content>
		<content>sinking</content> <!-- line 101 -->
		<content>this wreckage</content> <!-- line 102 -->
		<content>feel the beat</content> <!-- line 103 -->
		<content>love this storm</content>
		<content>you</content> <!-- line 105 -->
		<content>I</content>
		<content>storms brewing by</content> <!-- line 107 -->
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content>I know the sea</content> <!-- line 110 --> <!-- The Rotate words of the Storm Song Interlude -->
		<content>awake for hours</content>
		<content>streets of Manhattan</content>
		<content>the deluge</content>
		<content>hated his stubbornness</content>
		<content>angry gods</content>
		<content>Her last thought</content>
		<content>quench the flames</content>
		<content>central Pennsylvania</content>
		<content>happening out there</content> <!-- line 119 -->
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content>Love, This Storm</content> <!-- line 130 --> <!-- Beginning of Love This Storm -->
		<content id="style"><style>He wasn’t about to get out now — he didn’t care </style><style id="italic">what </style><style>Bloomberg said.</style></content>
		<content>Never, in his whole life, had he taken orders from anybody.</content>
		<content id="style"><style id="dark">Sure as </style><style>hell </style><style id="dark">he wasn’t about to start.</style></content>
		<content>Remy too had called and had begged him to leave, </content> <!-- line 134 -->
		<content>although he didn’t know why.</content>
		<content>She knew him better than anybody, in some ways better even than Jules.</content>
		<content>Maybe she just wanted to argue.</content> <!-- line 137 -->
		<content>It was her nature.</content>
		<content>Young,</content> <!-- line 139 -->
		<content>she had always hated his stubbornness</content>
		<content>as much as his absences,</content>
		<content>and had fought against it.</content>
		<content>Grown, she was no different.</content>
		<content>What did they know, though, surrounded by assistants,</content> <!-- line 144 -->
		<content>tucked away in the corner of some office?</content>
		<content id="style"><style>What </style><style id="italic">could </style><style>they know?</style></content> 
		<content>I’ve never had an office, he thought to himself.</content> <!-- line 147 -->
		<content>It was a matter of pride.</content>
		<content>Once, years ago,</content>
		<content>Remy had come home from school whimpering,</content>
		<content>Why can’t you be more like…?</content>
		<content>The blood had rushed to his head —</content>
		<content>even now he could feel that anger</content>
		<content>— he had snatched her up and taken her outside.</content> <!-- line 154 -->
		<content>There!</content> <!-- line 155 -->
		<content>he had shouted, pointing at the boat with his free hand.</content> 
		<content>That's my skyscraper!</content>
		<content>He had set her down forcibly,</content>
		<content>maybe too hard.</content>
		<content>Jules had ignored him for an entire week...</content>
		<content>I’ve never even had a desk.</content> <!-- line 161 -->
		<content id="style"><style>I know the </style><style>sea like it is a part of me;</style></content>
		<content id="style"><style id="portal">it’s my boss and my mistress.</style></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content>What Not to Wear During a Hurricane</content> <!-- line 170 -->
		<content>All week, she had been getting harried emails from clients and hundreds of comments on her blog from devoted fans, all asking her the same thing:</content>
		<content>What does one wear during a hurricane?</content>
<!-- line 173 --> <content id="style"><style>When discussing her clients’ options </style><style id="dark">over the phone or email </style><style>she listened closely to their concerns first, her long red nails in a steeple, her thin blonde hair parted aggressively and slicked back into a tight, low ponytail, her brows perfectly groomed under her giant sunglasses and her red lipstick perfectly applied. Once she knew their </style><style id="dark">style</style><style>, their lifestyle or upcoming events, and of course their </style><style id="dark">price range</style><style>, she could offer outfit suggestions, send them links to products, or just go out herself and pick up several exquisitely tasteful items for them.</style></content>
		<content>(or over a latte in a tucked-away, overpriced cafe if they happened to be one of her New York clients)</content>
		<content>(bohemian, preppy, retro...)</content>
		<content>(which was always satisfyingly high; it had to be, to afford a top celebrity stylist like herself)</content>
		<content>Some of her clients were A-list movie stars who needed just the right dress to exude an effortless glamour on the red carpet.</content> <!-- line 177 -->
		<content>Others were simply rich, bored society wives who wanted to look polished whether they were dropping the kids off at their selective preschool or accompanying their husband to the Met Gala.</content>
		<content>Right now, however, she was sitting at her lucite desk in her lucite chair, the attractive hardness of which had been softened with a sheepskin throw.</content> <!-- line 179 -->
		<content>The soft glow of her massive computer illuminated a few creases around her eyes and mouth, but no pores. It would be hard to say what color her eyes were.</content>
		<content>She drew her flowing caftan tighter over her shoulders and rubbed one bare foot over the other. She was thinking hard. Abruptly, as inspiration came to her, she attacked the keyboard to note:</content> <!-- line 181 -->
		<content>“Do NOT wear your favorite suede heels... You will regret it! Instead, consider those old Fendi motorcycle boots you have in the back of your closet (I know you do because we all do) or a simple pair of Bensimon sneakers if you feel like doing that French tomboy look. Bonus: they’re so cheap you can just throw them out if they get ruined from this never-ending rain. (I recommend a black maxi skirt with the boots and ripped boyfriend jeans with the Bensimons.)”</content>
		<content id="style"><style>She hit </style><style id="portal">publish </style><style>and then collapsed back against the chair as if this had taken the rest of her energy out of her.</style></content> <!-- line 183 -->
		<content id="style"><style>After a moment of staring blankly out the window at the raging storm, she sighed and got up, floating to the bedroom to shed the $1,000 cafta onto the floor. Glaring at the contents of her </style><style id="dark">walk-in closet, </style><style>she realized that this hurricane did present some difficulty for getting dressed.</style></content>
		<content>(walk-in? Well, of course — it was practically a room of its own)</content>
		<content>She thought it was important to be able to define one’s sense of style in one word, and thus she identified herself as bohemian. This explained all the long, flowing skirts and dresses that she would not be able to wear today without the rain ruining them.</content> <!-- line 186 -->
		<content>She furrowed her brow as she realized, peevishly, that her maxi skirt suggestion on her blog was probably not among her best. Oh well; too late to change it now. Most posts received hundreds of hits in the first couple of minutes after being published.</content>
		<content id="style"><style id="dark">In the end, she chose </style><style>pretty over practical.</style></content> <!-- line 188 -->
		<content id="style"><style id="dark">Her reasoning during dreary weather was that to reflect it in your clothes was to give in to it. Instead, she wore the happiest thing she could think of: </style><style>a knee-length pencil skirt </style><style id="dark">that was covered in </style><style>large, shimmering sequins </style><style id="dark">that resembled the </style><style>ocean sparkling in the summer.</style></content>
		<content>It was just the thing she needed. She felt certain that the rest of New York needed it too, so she tugged on her studded Chloe ankle boots and headed for the door. Swinging it open, she almost collided head-first with her husband.</content>
		<content>“Where do you think you’re going?” he demanded.</content> <!-- line 191 -->
		<content>“Out,” she said evasively, trying to slide her rail-thin body past his.</content>
		<content>“Not in this storm,” he said, and blocked her progress by sticking his arm across the doorway.</content>
		<content>“Oh, Robert,” she sighed exasperatedly. “I just have to run out for one super quick errand.”</content>
		<content>“Oh? What’s that? Cause I already got the water, batteries, and non-perishables,” he said, hoisting the brown paper bag in his other arm as proof. “What could you possibly have to get that’s so important?”</content>
		<content>She braced herself. “A very important client needs a dress for Letterman next week.” </content> <!-- line 196 -->
		<content id="style"><style>He stared at her in disbelief. “If you go out in this weather... for a </style><style id="italic">dress... </style><style>and wearing </style><style id="italic">that</style><style>...” He let the threat trail off.</style></content>
		<content>She bristled and shoved past him, her bony arms stronger than they looked thanks to years of lugging armfuls of clothes up and down the streets of Manhattan.</content> <!-- line 198 -->
		<content>She shouted to him without turning her head as she marched down the hall:</content> 
		<content>“I knew you hated this skirt!”</content>
		<content id="style"><style id="dark">He shook his head silently and watched with resignation as the elevator swallowed her whole, the </style><style>blue sequins </style><style id="dark">winking at him to the last.</style></content> <!-- line 201 -->
		<content>****</content>
		<content >Striding down her quiet, tree-lined block, she used her frustration with her husband for the strength needed to push back against the wind.</content> <!-- line 203 -->
		<content>He always trivialized her career.</content>
		<content id="style"><style>He didn’t realize how much people relied on her, </style><style id="italic">needed </style><style>her to look good, to feel good, to make or break </style><style id="italic">their </style><style>careers...</style></content>
		<content>She was so deep in her own thoughts that it took her three blocks before she realized that her numerous absent-minded attempts to flag down a cab were useless.</content> <!-- line 206 -->
		<content>There were no cabs.</content>
		<content id="style"><style id="dark">This seemed odd, so for the first time </style><style>she took note of her surroundings.</style></content>
		<content>Nobody else was in sight; she momentarily appeared to be the only person in the city until a van rushed by, making her jump and narrowly miss being splashed by dirty grey water.</content> <!-- line 209 -->
		<content>Fuming even more now (what if that had ruined her perfect chambray shirt?) she realized with dismay that to get to the boutique across town, she would have to take the subway. She had only done this a handful of times before, and every time it was a miserable experience.</content>
		<content>The sight of dull-faced people clad in equally dull clothing — worn suits, frumpy sweatpants — depressed her. Resigned, she headed for the nearest subway station, pursing her red lips tightly and ducking to avoid the debris and fallen tree branches being flung at her by the wind as she went.</content>
		<content>Heading down the steps into the subway station,</content> <!-- line 212 -->
		<content>she kept her head slightly down</content>
		<content>and her eyes on the damp concrete floor to avoid</content>
		<content id="style"><style id="dark">making eye contact with her </style><style>non-existent fellow subway riders.</style></content>
		<content>She felt the old panic of claustrophobia as the tiled walls closed in tighter, and tried not to breathe in too much of the stale air.</content> <!-- line 216 -->
		<content id="style"><style id="dark">She focused on her </style><style>glistening skirt</style><style id="dark">, the only source of light and color in the underground tunnel.</style></content>
		<content>She felt like it was smiling up at her, reassuring her that this place wasn’t where she belonged and that soon she would be above ground again, complacently browsing the clothing racks for the perfect gown.</content>
		<content>She had it pictured in her mind already: a mustard yellow gown with a deep V-neck, like the Vera Wang that Michelle wore to the 2006 Oscars with a handsome, still-alive Heath on her arm.</content> <!-- line 219 -->
		<content>This thought made her feel momentarily depressed again, so she brushed it off and began to</content>
		<content>descend the now-flooded escalator,</content>
		<content>grasping for lighter things to think about.</content>
		<content>She tried not to worry about whether her train would be delayed because of the water, or if she would have to take the skirt to the dry cleaners.</content> <!-- line 223 -->
		<content>Her last thought as she started to be</content>
		<content>submerged into the filmy, debris-littered pool</content>
		<content id="style"><style id="dark">was how pretty her </style><style>blue sequins </style><style id="dark">looked</style></content>
		<content>as their reflection sparkled in the dirty water.</content>
		<content id="style"><style>There was no doubt in </style><style id="portal"> her mind </style><style>that she was going to be</style></content> <!-- line 228 -->
		<content id="style"><style>the </style><style id="dark">best-dressed person </style><style>in the subway car.</style></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content>Storm Sisters</content> <!-- line 240 -->	
		<content>In the beginning, when the land was afire and the oceans boiled,</content>
		<content>the Sky Folk descended from the heavens to calm the raging world.</content>
		<content>Sky Father asked his people</content> <!-- line 243 -->	
		<content id="style"><style id="dark">how they could best </style><style>cool the earth,</style></content>
		<content>and they argued for many days until</content>
		<content id="style"><style id="dark">his </style><style>two youngest daughters </style><style id="dark">suggested they</style></content>
		<content>quench the flames with water.</content>
		<content>Together,</content> <!-- line 248 -->
		<content>the Sisters stirred the clouds</content>
		<content>until the winds roared</content>
		<content>and the rain fell thick as lead.</content>
		<content>After the earth had hissed and steamed</content>
		<content>for weeks under the deluge,</content>
		<content>the land was, at long last, cool and humid.</content> <!-- line 254 -->
		<content>The Sky Folk could touch the ground,</content>
		<content>and they made plants and animals by stirring</content>
		<content>the dust of their ancestors into the soil.</content>
		<content>But the Sisters were not happy.</content> <!-- line 258 -->
		<content>Obsessed with the fury of storms,</content>
		<content>they continued to frenzy the clouds,</content>
		<content>nearly flooding the entire land.</content>
		<content>They threw lightning</content>
		<content>at the Sky Folk who opposed them</content>
		<content>and hurled snow upon the earth.</content>
		<content>Finally,</content> <!-- line 265 -->
		<content>Sky Father grew weary</content>
		<content>of the Sisters' tyranny,</content> 
		<content>and he trapped them</content>
		<content>beneath a pile of rock.</content>
		<content>The snow melted</content>
		<content>and life flourished for a while;</content>
		<content>however, soon after,</content>
		<content>the water dried</content>
		<content>and the plants withered.</content>
		<content>Sky Father realized the clouds</content> <!-- line 275 -->
		<content>needed to be emptied once again;</content> 
		<content>he remembered his daughters,</content>
		<content>and in exchange for their freedom,</content>
		<content>they agreed to only make storms</content>
		<content>when it was necessary.</content>
		<content>After that, the earth and its people were at peace.</content>
		<content>But the Sisters still loved</content> <!-- line 282 -->
		<content>the might of their tempest.</content>
		<content>Every few moons,</content>
		<content>when Sky Father was not there,</content>
		<content>they would again create</content>
		<content>terrible storms…</content>
		<content>If the clouds ever</content> <!-- line 288 -->
		<content>look gray and menacing,</content>
		<content>pray that Sky Father</content>
		<content>is watching</content> <!-- line 291 -->
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content></content>
		<content>Sound Effects of Perfect Thunder Storm and Distant Thunder</content> <!-- line 300 -->
		<content>courtesy of Mike Koenig and www.soundbible.com</content>
		<content>"Before the Hurricane" photo</content>
		<content>courtesy of Valerie Morales</content>
		<content>"Follow" us for more experiments with multimedia art</content> <!-- line 304 -->
		<content>(artwork, stories, music, interactivity, photography, sounds)</content>
		<content>What would you like to see? Comments? Critiques?</content>
		<content id="style"><style id="portal">Submit some feedback </style><style> or drop us a comment below</style></content>
		<content id="style"><style id="portal">Submit some feedback</style></content> <!-- line 308 -->
	</text>
</root>